# Abimbola Balogun

# **Frontend Engineer**

Address Ottawa, ON K2V 0P4

WWW https://bold.pro/my/abimbola-balogun/638r

**Phone** +1(613)-978-4243

E-mail olorunyomi97@gmail.com

With 5+ years of experience in React, React Native, and Javascript. Specialized in building and maintaining web and mobile applications for thousands of users, focusing on application security, responsiveness, and scalability. A team player with strong communication skills, committed to creating effective solutions that align with business needs.

# Websites

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/abimbola-balogun-84a68011a/
- https://github.com/olorunyomi97

### Skills

#### **Programming Languages**

JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, HTML&CSS, Sass, PHP, GraphQL

#### Libraries & Frameworks

React, React Native, VueJs, Next.Js, Gatsby, Node.Js, ExpressJs, Tailwind CSS, Styled Components, Laravel.

#### **Tools & Platforms**

Git, GitHub, BitBucket, Netlify, Vercel, Heroku, Digital Ocean, AWS, Firebase, Storybook, Webpack, Figma, MongoDB, phpMyAdmin

# Experience

#### 2023-04 - 2024-06

## **Frontend Developer**

Tunga, Amsterdam

- Utilized React Native to design and implement responsive, high-performance user interfaces for a mobile application called Fanect, ensuring a seamless user experience across both iOS and Android platforms.
- Collaborated with UI/UX designers to translate wireframes and mockups into interactive and visually appealing mobile app screens, focusing on user engagement and accessibility
- Employed ReactJS to build and enhance the admin dashboard, creating intuitive and efficient management tools for administrators to monitor and manage user activities, content, and analytics.
- Managed deployment processes using Cloudways and AWS, ensuring reliable and scalable hosting solutions for both the mobile application. This included setting up continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) pipelines, monitoring server performance, and optimizing resource usage to ensure high availability and low latency.
- Utilized Firebase to ensure secure and scalable delivery of the admin dashboard application updates and real-time database management for user-generated content.

#### **Fullstack Software Developer**

#### OnePort 365, Lagos

- Co-Led a cross-functional team to develop West Africa's first digital freight forwarding management application, serving 10,000+ clients.
- Developed a comprehensive booking system for freight forwarding using Typescript for the front end development, allowing customers to select shipment types (Import/ Export) and desired services including Ocean Freight, Haulage, Air Freight, Custom Brokerage and Warehousing
- Built, styled, and shipped high quality websites, design systems, mobile apps, and cross-platform digital experiences
  for a diverse array of clients using technologies such as JavaScript, TypeScript, React, CSS, WordPress, Contentful,
  and more
- Championed the setup and configuration of a React based application, accurately translating complex designs into functional interfaces, architecting optimized database schemas, and crafting robust API endpoints.
- Provided leadership within engineering department through close collaboration, building tools to improve developer experience, and mentorship

# **2019-12 - 2022-02 Frontend Developer**

LeniLabs, Lagos

- Implemented a highly developed GraphQL APIs for a high-traffic e-commerce web applications
  (https://www.artgidi.com/), improving data retrieval efficiency by 30% as well as building GraphQL queries and
  mutations to streamline data access, resulting in a 25% reduction in backend response times.
- Deployed and developed scalable GraphQL schemas for a SaaS application (https://www.mayfairdesignstudio.ng/),
   enhancing client-side data fetching and reducing payload sizes by 20%
- Created intuitive admin dashboards for e-commerce and e-Library applications, improving user management and data analysis, resulting in a 30% boost in productivity and data-driven decision-making.
- Crafted professional and responsive websites for corporate firms, showcasing their brand identity and driving online presence, resulting in a 40% increase in website traffic and user engagement.
- Engineered a web application for dispatch operations, integrating Google Maps for precise geolocation services, optimizing delivery efficiency by 25% and reducing transportation costs by 15%.
- Solicited and incorporated feedback from colleagues to streamline the software development life cycle, resulting in a 20% reduction in development time and improved team efficiency.

# Education

# 2014-10 - 2019-05 Bsc in Chemical Engineering

University of Lagos - Lagos, Lagos

# Languages

English



#### **Interests**

Web Accessibility, Anime, Gaming, Gym